<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Physics on Godot 4 Recipes</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Physics on Godot 4 Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RigidBody2D: Look at Target</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/smooth_rigid_rotate/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/smooth_rigid_rotate/index.html</guid><description>Problem You want a rigid body to rotate smoothly to look at a target.
Solution Using RigidBody2D can be tricky. Because it&amp;rsquo;s controlled by Godot&amp;rsquo;s physics engine, you need to apply forces rather than moving it directly. Before doing anything with rigid bodies, I highly recommend looking at the RigidBody2D API doc.
To rotate a body, we need to apply a rotational force - a torque. Once the body is rotating, we want the torque to get smaller as we get closer to the final rotation.</description></item><item><title>RigidBody2D: Drag and Drop</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/rigidbody_drag_drop/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/rigidbody_drag_drop/index.html</guid><description>Problem You want to pick up and move rigid bodies with the mouse.
Solution Working with rigid bodies can be tricky. Godot&amp;rsquo;s physics engine controls their movements, and interfering with that can often lead to unexpected results. The key is to make use of the body&amp;rsquo;s mode property. This applies equally well in 2D or 3D.
Body setup We&amp;rsquo;ll start with our rigid body object, adding a Sprite2D and CollisionShape2D. You can also add a PhysicsMaterial if you want to set Bounce and Friction properties.</description></item><item><title>Character to Rigid Body Interaction</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/character_vs_rigid/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/character_vs_rigid/index.html</guid><description>Problem You want your character body to interact with rigid bodies.
Solution Note This recipe applies equally well in both 2D and 3D nodes.
By default, a CharacterBody2D moved with move_and_slide() or move_and_collide() will not push any RigidBody2D it collides with. The rigid body doesn&amp;rsquo;t react at all, and behaves just like a StaticBody2D.
In some cases, this might be all you need. However, if you want to be able to push the bodies, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to make some changes.</description></item><item><title>Asteroids-style Physics (using RigidBody2D)</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/asteroids_physics/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/physics/asteroids_physics/index.html</guid><description>Problem You want to use a RigidBody2D to create a semi-realistic spaceship, a la Asteroids.
Solution Using RigidBody2D can be tricky. Because it&amp;rsquo;s controlled by Godot&amp;rsquo;s physics engine, you need to apply forces rather than moving it directly. Before doing anything with rigid bodies, I highly recommend looking at the RigidBody2D API doc, and we&amp;rsquo;ll refer to it as we work through this example.
For this example, we&amp;rsquo;ll use the following node setup:</description></item></channel></rss>