<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Input on Godot Recipes by KidsCanCode</title>
    <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Input on Godot Recipes by KidsCanCode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:47:11 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Input Actions</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/input_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/input_actions/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to understand Godot&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;input action&amp;rdquo; system.
Solution Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re making a top-down character and you write code using InputActionKey that uses the arrow keys for movement. You&amp;rsquo;ll quickly find that many players prefer to use &amp;ldquo;WASD&amp;rdquo; style controls. You can go back into your code and add the additional key checks, but this would result in duplicated/redundant code.
Input actions can help to make your code more configurable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse Input</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_input/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to detect mouse input.
Solution InputEventMouse is the base class for mouse events. It contains position and global_position properties. Inheriting from it are two classes: InputEventMouseButton and InputEventMouseMotion.
You can assign mouse button events in the InputMap, so you can use them with is_action_pressed().
 InputEventMouseButton @GlobalScope.ButtonList contains a list of BUTTON_* constants for each possible button, which will be reported in the event’s button_index property. Note that the scrollwheel also counts as a button - two buttons, to be precise, with both BUTTON_WHEEL_UP and BUTTON_WHEEL_DOWN being separate events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Input Actions in code</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/custom_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/custom_actions/</guid>
      <description>Problem You need to add actions to the InputMap at runtime.
Solution Typically, you&amp;rsquo;ll add actions to the InputMap via Project Settings, as shown in Recipe: Input Actions. However, you may find yourself needing to add one or more actions directly in a script. TheInputMap singleton has methods to help you do this.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example that would add a new action called &amp;ldquo;attack&amp;rdquo; using the space key:
func _ready(): InputMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capturing the Mouse</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_capture/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to hide the mouse cursor and keep the mouse from leaving the game window. This is common in many 3D games (and some 2D ones).
Solution You can set the mouse state using Input.set_mouse_mode(). There are four possible mouse modes:
 MOUSE_MODE_VISIBLE: The mouse is visible and can move freely into and out of the window. This is the default state.
 MOUSE_MODE_HIDDEN: The mouse cursor is invisible, but the mouse can still move outside the window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing the Mouse Cursor</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/custom_mouse_cursor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/custom_mouse_cursor/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to use a custom mouse cursor.
Solution Setting the mouse cursor is done with Input.set_custom_mouse_cursor(). All you need is a texture to use. The texture must be no larger than 256x256 pixels in size.
For example, to use the following image:
And set its hotspot to the center:
extends Node2D func _ready(): Input.set_custom_mouse_cursor(cursor_image, Input.CURSOR_ARROW, Vector2(64, 64)) The second parameter sets which system cursor to replace. See the Input docs for the full list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse: Drag-select multiple units</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/multi_unit_select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/multi_unit_select/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to click-and-drag to select multiple units, RTS style.
Solution Realtime strategy (RTS) games often require giving orders to many units at once. A typical style of selecting multiple units is to click-and-drag a box around them. Once the units are selected, clicking on the map commands them to move.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what we&amp;rsquo;re going for:
Unit setup To test this out, we&amp;rsquo;ll need some basic RTS-style units.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>