<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to 3D on Godot 4 Recipes</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Intro to 3D on Godot 4 Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The 3D Editor</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_01/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_01/index.html</guid><description>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to start working in 3D in Godot. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to navigate in the 3D editor, how to create and manipulate 3D objects, and how to work with some of Godot&amp;rsquo;s essential 3D nodes, such as cameras and lighting.
Are you ready? A word of warning: 3D development can be quite a bit more complex than working in 2D. While many of the same principles apply - such as working with nodes, writing scripts, and handling logic/data - 3D brings with it a number of other considerations.</description></item><item><title>Importing 3D Objects</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_02/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_02/index.html</guid><description>In the last part, we started a 3D project and looked at how to navigate and create 3D objects. In this part, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to import existing 3D objects that you&amp;rsquo;ve made or downloaded and how to use more of Godot&amp;rsquo;s 3D nodes.
Importing 3D Objects If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with 3D modeling software such as Blender, you can make your own models to use in your game. If not, there are many sources where you can download objects or even collections of objects for particular game types.</description></item><item><title>Creating a 3D Character</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_03/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/4.x/g101/3d/101_3d_03/index.html</guid><description>In the last part, we covered how to import 3D objects and how to arrange them in a scene. In this installment, we&amp;rsquo;ll add more objects to the scene, including a user-controlled character.
Building the Scene We&amp;rsquo;re going to continue using the Kenney Platformer Kit we downloaded in Part 2. Select all the block*.glb files and in the Import tab set their Root Type to StaticBody3D. Uncheck the Root Name property and click Reimport.</description></item></channel></rss>