<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Know Your Nodes on Godot 3 Recipes</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/index.html</link><description>Recent content in Know Your Nodes on Godot 3 Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Label</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/label/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/label/index.html</guid><description>Label Label is a Control node for displaying unformatted text, with options for controlling the text&amp;rsquo;s alignment, wrapping, etc.
API Documentation
Node properties See the documentation for the full list, but here we&amp;rsquo;ll review the most commonly used properties of the node:
text - this property is the contents of the label. Change this in code to change what the label displays. If you&amp;rsquo;re displaying numerical values, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to convert them to strings!</description></item><item><title>Path2D &amp; PathFollow2D</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/path2d/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/path2d/index.html</guid><description>Path2D &amp;amp; PathFollow2D A path is a sequence of points in 2D space, defined by a Curve2D resource. The Path2D is a node that allows you to position a path in 2D space, and do create a new path in the editor.
Paths have a variety of uses. You can make a patrol path for an enemy mob to follow, a winding path for an animated visual effect, a pattern for a moving platform to follow, etc.</description></item><item><title>RayCast2D</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/raycast2d/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/raycast2d/index.html</guid><description>RayCast2D Raycasting is a common technique in game development. &amp;ldquo;Casting a ray&amp;rdquo; means extending a line from a point until it collides with something or reaches its limit.
Node properties Add a RayCast2D node and take a look at the Inspector:
Here are the main properties you&amp;rsquo;ll need to understand:
Enabled Turn this on to make the raycast work. This property is disabled by default!
Exclude Parent This property causes the ray to ignore collisions with the parent object.</description></item><item><title>RigidBody2D</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/rigidbody2d/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/rigidbody2d/index.html</guid><description>RigidBody2D RigidBody2D is the physics body in Godot that provides simulated physics. This means that you don’t control a RigidBody2Ddirectly. Instead you apply forces to it (gravity, impulses, etc.) and Godot’s built-in physics engine calculates the resulting movement, including collisions, bouncing, rotating, etc.
Warning Setting a RigidBody2D&amp;rsquo;s physical properties, such as position or linear_velocity directly will not work correctly. The physics engine controls these values.
The body’s behavior is also affected by the world, via the Project Settings -&amp;gt; Physics properties, or by entering an Area2D that is overriding the global physics properties.</description></item><item><title>YSort</title><link>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/ysort/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://godotrecipes.com/godot_recipes/3.x/kyn/ysort/index.html</guid><description>YSort Many 2D games use a &amp;ldquo;3/4 view&amp;rdquo; perspective, giving the impression that the camera is looking at the world at an angle. However, to make this art style work, objects that are &amp;ldquo;farther&amp;rdquo; away should be rendered behind &amp;ldquo;nearer&amp;rdquo; objects. In practice, we want to &amp;ldquo;y sort&amp;rdquo;, or make the drawing order tied to the object&amp;rsquo;s y coordinate: the higher on the screen, the farther away and therefore the lower the render order.</description></item></channel></rss>