<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Godot Recipes by KidsCanCode</title>
    <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Godot Recipes by KidsCanCode</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 22:57:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3D Editor</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:23:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_01/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to start working in 3D in Godot. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to navigate in the 3D editor, how to create and manipulate 3D objects, and how to work with some of Godot&amp;rsquo;s essential 3D nodes, such as cameras and lighting.
Are you ready? A word of warning: 3D development can be quite a bit more complex than working in 2D. While many of the same principles apply - such as working with nodes, writing scripts, and handling logic/data - 3D brings with it a number of other considerations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Godot?</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:23:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_01/</guid>
      <description>Game Engines Game development is complex and involves a wide variety of knowledge and skills. In order to build a modern game, you need a lot of underlying technology before you can make the actual game itself. Imagine if you had to build your own computer and write your own operating system before you could even start programming. Game development would be a lot like that if you truly had to start from scratch and build everything you needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capturing the Mouse</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_capture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_capture/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to hide the mouse cursor and keep the mouse from leaving the game window. This is common in many 3D games (and some 2D ones).
Solution You can set the mouse state using Input.set_mouse_mode(). There are four possible mouse modes:
 MOUSE_MODE_VISIBLE: The mouse is visible and can move freely into and out of the window. This is the default state.
 MOUSE_MODE_HIDDEN: The mouse cursor is invisible, but the mouse can still move outside the window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entering/Exiting the screen</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/enter_exit_screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/enter_exit_screen/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to detect when an object enters or exits the screen.
Solution The engine provides a node for this: VisibilityNotifier2D. Attach this node to your object, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use its screen_entered and screen_exited signals.
Example 1 Consider a projectile that travels in a straight line after it&amp;rsquo;s fired. If we continue firing, eventually we&amp;rsquo;ll have a large number of objects for the engine to track, event though they&amp;rsquo;re offscreen, which can cause lag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpolation</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/math/interpolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/math/interpolation/</guid>
      <description>Interpolation, or its commonly-used abbreviation lerp, is a term that comes up often in game development. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never come across it before it can seem mysterious and highly-technical, but as you&amp;rsquo;ll see in this tutorial, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a straightforward concept with a wide variety of applications in game programming.
Numeric Interpolation The core formula for linear interpolation is this:
func lerp(a, b, t): return (1 - t) * a + t * b In this formula, a and b represent the two values and t is the amount of interpolation, typically expressed as a value between 0 (which returns a), and 1 (which returns b).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mouse Input</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/input/mouse_input/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to detect mouse input.
Solution InputEventMouse is the base class for mouse events. It contains position and global_position properties. Inheriting from it are two classes: InputEventMouseButton and InputEventMouseMotion.
You can assign mouse button events in the InputMap, so you can use them with is_action_pressed().
 InputEventMouseButton @GlobalScope.ButtonList contains a list of BUTTON_* constants for each possible button, which will be reported in the event’s button_index property. Note that the scrollwheel also counts as a button - two buttons, to be precise, with both BUTTON_WHEEL_UP and BUTTON_WHEEL_DOWN being separate events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Healthbars</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/ui/unit_healthbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/ui/unit_healthbar/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want units in your game to have healthbars that follow them as they move.
Solution Displaying the bar can be done with a TextureProgress node. This is like the ProgressBar node, but allows the use of textures for the bar itself. The length of the bar will indicate the health value, but we can also change the texture color. We&amp;rsquo;ll use three colored bars for this:
So that this bar can be added to any unit in the game, we&amp;rsquo;ll make it a separate scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Platform character</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/platform_character/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/platform_character/</guid>
      <description>Problem You need to make a 2D platform-style character.
Solution New developers are often surprised at how complex a platform character can be to program. Godot provides some built-in tools to assist, but there are as many solutions as there are games. In this tutorial, we won&amp;rsquo;t be going in-depth with features like double-jumps, crouching, wall-jumps, or animation. Here we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the fundamentals of platformer movement. See the rest of the recipes for other solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project setup</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_01/</guid>
      <description>Where to start? Depending on the game, and how fleshed-out your idea is, the answer might be very different. In our case, I&amp;rsquo;ve cheated a little bit by making a prototype of the game already and working out a few of the ideas ahead of time. Still, it diverged a bit from my initial idea, and so might this series - time will tell.
In a bigger project, you might start with design document, which could be as simple as a page of notes or as complex as a 500-page treatise laying out every detail of your game&amp;rsquo;s world, plot, and mechanics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Screen wrap</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/screen_wrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/screen_wrap/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to allow the player to &amp;ldquo;wrap around&amp;rdquo; the screen, teleporting from one side of the screen to the other. This is a common feature, especially in old-school 2D games (think Pac-man).
Solution  Get your screen (viewport) size
onready var screen_size = get_viewport_rect().size get_viewport_rect() is available to any CanvasItem derived node.
 Compare your player&amp;rsquo;s position
if position.x &amp;gt; screen_size.x: position.x = 0 if position.x &amp;lt; 0: position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Splitscreen multiplayer</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/splitscreen_demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/splitscreen_demo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In this demo, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider a local multiplayer game - a topdown-style maze game with two players (one using arrow keys and the other using WASD controls). This is not a problem if our game world all fits on one screen, but if the map is large, we&amp;rsquo;ll want to have a &amp;ldquo;split screen&amp;rdquo; view tracking the two players separately.
We&amp;rsquo;ll also look at a quick way to set up a minimap display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TileMap: detecting tiles</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/tilemap_collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/tilemap_collision/</guid>
      <description>Problem You have a KinematicBody2D character colliding with a TileMap, and you want to know which tile it collided with.
Solution When a KinematicBody2D collides, the collision data is returned in a KinematicCollision2D object. The TileMap acts as a single collider, so if you reference the collider property, it will be the TileMap node.
You then need to find out which tile in the TileMap is at the collision location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top-down character</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/topdown_movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/topdown_movement/</guid>
      <description>Problem You&amp;rsquo;re making a 2D top-down game, and you want to control a character&amp;rsquo;s movement.
Solution For this solution, we&amp;rsquo;ll assume you have the following input actions defined:
   Action Name Key(s)     &amp;quot;up&amp;quot; W,↑   &amp;quot;down&amp;quot; S,↓   &amp;quot;right&amp;quot; D,→   &amp;quot;left&amp;quot; A,←   &amp;quot;click&amp;quot; Mouse button 1    We will also assume you&amp;rsquo;re using a KinematicBody2D character.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Godot&#39;s Editor: Finding your way around</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:23:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_02/</guid>
      <description>Project Manager The Project Manager is the first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll see when opening Godot.
In this window you can see a list of your Godot projects. You can choose an existing project and click &amp;ldquo;Run&amp;rdquo; to play the game or click &amp;ldquo;Edit&amp;rdquo; to work on it in the Godot editor. Since you probably don&amp;rsquo;t have any projects yet, let&amp;rsquo;s start by clicking the &amp;ldquo;New Project&amp;rdquo; button.
Here you can give the project a name and create a folder to store it in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing 3D Objects</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:22:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_02/</guid>
      <description>In the last part, we started a 3D project and looked at how to navigate and create 3D objects. In this part, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to import existing 3D objects that you&amp;rsquo;ve made or downloaded and how to use more of Godot&amp;rsquo;s 3D nodes.
Importing 3D Objects If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with 3D modeling software such as Blender, you can make your own models to use in your game. If not, there are many sources where you can download objects or even collections of objects for particular game types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spawning Circles</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_02/</guid>
      <description>In the previous part, we created the Jumper and Circle object that make up the bulk of the game. Now we need to add the progression: a continuous series of spawned circles as long as the player doesn&amp;rsquo;t miss.
Expanding the Main scene Let&amp;rsquo;s add some more nodes to Main:
 Position2D (&amp;ldquo;StartPosition&amp;rdquo;)
This will mark the starting position for the game. Place it near the bottom-center of the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodes: Godot&#39;s building blocks</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 20:23:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/start/101_03/</guid>
      <description>Nodes are the basic building blocks for creating games in Godot. A node is an object that can represent some kind of specialized game function. A given type of node might display graphics, play an animation, or represent a 3D model of an object. The node also contains a collection of properties, allowing you to customize its behavior. Which nodes you add to your project will depend on what functionality you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transforms</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/math/transforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 19:49:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/math/transforms/</guid>
      <description>Before reading this, make sure you have an understanding of vectors and how they&amp;rsquo;re used in game development. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, I recommend you read this introduction I wrote for the Godot documentation: Vector Math.
2D Transforms In 2D space, we use the familiar X-Y coordinate plane. Remember that in Godot, as in most computer graphics applications, the Y axis points downward:
To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s consider this spaceship floating in space:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a 3D Character</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:22:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_03/</guid>
      <description>In the last part, we covered how to import 3D objects and how to arrange them in a scene. In this installment, we&amp;rsquo;ll add more objects to the scene, including a user-controlled character.
Building the Scene We&amp;rsquo;re going to continue using the Kenney Platformer Kit we downloaded last time. Select all the &amp;ldquo;block*.glb&amp;rdquo; files and in the &amp;ldquo;Import&amp;rdquo; tab set their &amp;ldquo;Root Type&amp;rdquo; to StaticBody and click &amp;ldquo;Reimport&amp;rdquo;. Select &amp;ldquo;blockLarge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinematic Friction</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/kinematic_friction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/kinematic_friction/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to add friction and acceleration to your kinematic character, giving it a smoother feel.
Solution For most games, we&amp;rsquo;re not necessarily interested in a perfect physics simulation. We want action, responsiveness, and arcade feel. This is why you choose a kinematic body over a rigid one: so that you can control its behavior directly. However, some amount of physics is good - it means an object doesn&amp;rsquo;t instantly change direction or come to a stop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Limited circles</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_03/</guid>
      <description>In the first two parts, we got the basic gameplay working. Now we&amp;rsquo;re going to start adding some different modes to the circles.
Circle modes Eventually, we&amp;rsquo;ll have many different modes, but we&amp;rsquo;re going to start with the &amp;ldquo;limited&amp;rdquo; mode: the circle only allows a given number of orbits before disappearing. First, let&amp;rsquo;s add a Label node to show the number of remaining orbits. Type a number (1) in the text field so we can see how it looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Areas</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:22:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_04/</guid>
      <description>In the last part, we learned about transforms, a very important concept in 3D that records an object&amp;rsquo;s local orientation in space, and used it to move our KinematicBody character. This time, we&amp;rsquo;re going to look at another type of 3D node: the Area.
Areas Area nodes are used for detection and influence. They can detect when objects overlap, and when an object enters or exits a region. An Area can also be used to override physics properties, such as gravity or damping, in a region.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling animations</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/animation/animation_state_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/animation/animation_state_machine/</guid>
      <description>Problem A common situation: you have a large number of animations, and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming difficult to manage transitions between them. Your code has become full of if statements, and every time you change something, it all breaks.
Solution Use an AnimationTree to create an animation state machine. This will allow us to organize our animations and most importantly, control the transitions between them.
Getting started For this demo, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the excellent &amp;ldquo;Adventurer&amp;rdquo; sprite by Elthen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Menus</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_04/</guid>
      <description>Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve got the basic gameplay, it&amp;rsquo;s time to start working on the UI. We&amp;rsquo;re going to need menu screens for the title, settings, and game over.
Menu screens The three screens will share a common layout and some functionality, so we&amp;rsquo;ll start with a base scene they can all inherit from. In the new scene, start with a CanvasLayer and name it BaseScreen. Save this scene in the &amp;ldquo;UI&amp;rdquo; folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spritesheet animation</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/animation/spritesheet_animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/animation/spritesheet_animation/</guid>
      <description>Problem You want to use a spritesheet containing 2D animations.
Solution Spritesheets are a common way for 2D animations to be distributed. In a spritesheet, all of the animation frames are packed into a single image.
For this demo, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the excellent &amp;ldquo;Adventurer&amp;rdquo; sprite by Elthen. You can get this and lots of other great art athttps://elthen.itch.io/.
Make sure the images in your spritesheet are laid out in a constant-sized grid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using autotile</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/autotile_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/2d/autotile_intro/</guid>
      <description>Problem You are using a TileMap, and want to use autotiling to more quickly draw your levels.
Solution For this demo, we&amp;rsquo;ll be using the following tileset:
These tiles are from Kenney&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Topdown Shooter&amp;rdquo; art pack, which you can find here:https://kenney.nl/assets/topdown-shooter
 Creating a map from these tiles, if you were adding them one-by-one, would be a tedious process. You would be constantly changing between tiles to line up corners, intersections, and endpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edge Detection &amp; Mouse Capture</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 05:22:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_05/</guid>
      <description>In the last part, we learned how to use Area nodes to detect contact between objects, making coin, bullet, and spike objects for our character to interact with. In this part, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few small improvements: capturing the mouse, animating the coins, and detecting edges so our character doesn&amp;rsquo;t fall.
Capturing the Mouse One issue with our mouse-based controls is that as you move the mouse from side to side, it eventually moves out of the game window and hits the edge of your screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Score and HUD</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_05/</guid>
      <description>In the last part, we added UI in the form of menus to start and configure the game. We also need a UI to display in-game information such as score.
HUD scene Add a new scene with a CanvasLayer root to be our HUD. Give it two children: a MarginContainer named &amp;ldquo;ScoreBox&amp;rdquo; and a `Label&amp;rdquo; named &amp;ldquo;Message&amp;rdquo;.
Your scene tree should look like this:
Set the layout of the ScoreBox to &amp;ldquo;Bottom Wide&amp;rdquo; and the Custom Constants all to 20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound and Colors</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/games/circle_jump/circle_jump_06/</guid>
      <description>Settings singleton First, we&amp;rsquo;ll add a new script by choosing File -&amp;gt; New Script in the script tab. Name the script settings.gd.
In this script we&amp;rsquo;ll place the configuration settings for the game.
var enable_sound = true var enable_music = true var circles_per_level = 5 Add the script as an autoload by opening &amp;ldquo;Project Settings&amp;rdquo; and selecting the &amp;ldquo;Autoloads&amp;rdquo; tab. Click the folder to load the script and then click &amp;ldquo;Add&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CSG</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_06/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, we saw how to design a 3D environment using imported models. But what if you want to make something like a room, with walls, doors, ramps, and other features, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have any models handy? CSG to the rescue!
What is CSG? CSG stands for Constructive Solid Geometry. It allows you to combine primitive shapes to build complex geometry. Shapes can be combined with boolean operations such as Union, Intersection, and Subtraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First-person Character</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/g101/3d/101_3d_07/</guid>
      <description>In this installment, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at how to make a first-person character. We&amp;rsquo;ll use the CSG-based level we designed in the previous part as a place to walk around and test our movement.
Character Scene In an FPS or similar game, we want to give the player the illusion that they&amp;rsquo;re looking out of the character&amp;rsquo;s eyes. One nice aspect of this is that we don&amp;rsquo;t really need a model, at least to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using KinematicBody2D</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/godot3_kinematic2d/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 03:12:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/godot3_kinematic2d/</guid>
      <description>Godot offers a number of collision objects to provide both collision detection and response. Trying to decide which one to use for your project can be confusing. You can avoid problems and simplify development if you understand how each each works and what their pros and cons are. In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the KinematicBody2D node and show some examples of how it can be used.
Introduction: Physics bodies In game development you often need to know when two objects in the game space intersect or come into contact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inheritance</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/recipes/godot3_inheritance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 15:12:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/recipes/godot3_inheritance/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how inheritance works in Godot. You can use inheritance in Godot to reuse code and create powerful hierarchies of object and scenes in your game.
We&amp;rsquo;ll imagine we&amp;rsquo;re making a classic top-down RPG and use Godot&amp;rsquo;s inheritance capabilities to create two different kinds of characters in the game.
Introduction In object oriented programming (OOP), inheritance is a powerful tool. Put briefly, you can define a class that inherits from another class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Rigid Bodies</title>
      <link>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/godot3_kyn_rigidbody1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 08:12:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kidscancode.org/godot_recipes/physics/godot3_kyn_rigidbody1/</guid>
      <description>At the time of this writing, Godot 3.0 is nearing release, and many new users are trying it out. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a lot of confusion around physics and physics bodies, especially rigid bodies, which are Godot&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; physics nodes.
In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain when (and when not) to use rigid bodies, how they work, and demonstrate a few handy tricks to bend them to your will. The examples will use RigidBody2D, but the lessons apply equally to 3D.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>